Okay.
We've got a couple of consumers to go because we've got a couple of contracts that we haven't dealt
with yet.
The auction updated and the auction deleted.
And if we go to our auctions controller, then we've got the endpoints in here already for this functionality.
But we need to publish this to the service bus using the outbox that we've already configured obviously
for the auction service and do the same for the delete auction as well.
Now your mentor has taken a break and he's decided this is a good opportunity for you to get your hands
dirty and give this a go yourself.
Now, the goal of this particular challenge is if we go to Postman, we can see in this checkpoint folder
there are several tests and we've got one to create a new auction, same as what we've been using before,
but with a random first name instead of a grid.
And then we've got a test to make sure that was created in the search service, same as before.
Then we've got a request to go and update the auction.
And this is simply going to populate these properties along with an updated property on the created
item model.
And then we're going to go and get the updated item from search and expect that to contain updated following
that, we're going to delete the auction and then we're going to make sure the auction has been deleted
all inside the search service as well.
So we don't have consumers for this yet.
So if I run these tests and I click on the checkpoint folder and click Run.
And we'll look at this 150% used.
I wonder if this is going to start failing soon because I keep running these tests, but I'm going to
try it again.
But if I run this, then it's going to go through and execute all these requests.
But I've got two failing tests and this is getting the item updated from the search service and getting
the item created.
Is returning a result because something hasn't been deleted from the search service.
So we want all of these tests to pass and that will be the goal that you're trying to reach for this
particular challenge.
Now, don't worry if you don't get this working or you get stuck or whatever, you can always refer
to the repository, the demo repository on GitHub for this training course to give you a few hints.
If you get stuck, you'll also need to review the documentation for MongoDB entities to do things that
we haven't done yet.
And if we take a look at the entities, then we've got the update options and delete options.
So please do take a look at the documentation here to get a few clues about what you can do for this.
And just as a small hint, the one that I chose to use to do this is to use the modify only the properties
that we're expecting to be updated.
Also, you'll need to think about the mapping configuration to go from the auction entity and the update
method to the auction updated contracts that we have.
So there's a few things to think about and it's a mildly challenging challenge to get this working.
So please do give it a go and you'll know you're successful because all of these tests will pass and
just to demonstrate that point.
So once you've configured your consumers, then what you should be able to do is run the tests inside
this checkpoint.
But whilst you're going through this and you're creating your consumers, just run these individually
just so you can make sure and see what you're doing as you're going through these.
Don't be afraid to use the debugger as well.
If you want to find out what's going on and what you've got inside your message, what you're doing.
Also, whether or not you're using Automapper, have you got that configured correctly, those sort
of things.
So please give this a go.
But don't worry if you get stuck on this because I'm going to go through what I did very shortly to
get this done.
But what you should find is that once you have this configured, then when you run these requests,
then you should find that all of the tests pass and none of them fail.
And the auction gets created when we update it in the search service.
Then when we get the updated item from that search service, we get that with the updated field, which
is what's happening.
When we do update the auction, then we go ahead and delete it.
And the final test is to make sure that we cannot find it in the database and we get zero results when
we search for something with that name.
So please do give this a go.
Like I say, I'm going to run through it with you anyway afterwards.
So good luck with this and I'll see you in the next lesson to show you what I did to achieve this.