Okay.
Hopefully you gave that a go and you got success with your tests when you ran the checkpoint test inside
here.
If you didn't, don't worry.
I'm going to go through what I did to get that working.
So starting off in the auctions controller from the auction service, of course, we need to add the
publish endpoint so that when we update the auction, we publish that endpoint and I don't need that
auction updated there because the publish knows what type this is going to be.
But I've got a mapping in here for the auction updated to go from the auction entity to the auction
updated.
So I'll just open up the mapping profiles for the auction service and inside here for the auction to
the auction.
Updated I've also included members because we are updating item properties and then I've got the extra
mapping we need to go from the item to the auction updated and then we go ahead and publish this endpoint.
Notice that it's before we get to the save changes.
So if our service bus was down, then this would still work and it would save that message into the
outbox in our database when the service bus comes back up, then of course it would be published and
then we just return.
Okay, as normal.
So from the other side of things, when our search service receives that, then inside the solution,
inside search service, I've got an auction updated consumer.
Now, this one might have been a bit tricky because I'm not expecting you to know anything about MongoDB
entities, so you might have had to spend a bit of time in the docs and trying and failing a few times
to get the right configuration to save or update something in a database.
I remember when I first gave it a go, I managed to reset all of the properties to Null the first time
because I chose to use a short solution rather than modifying only the properties that I was interested
in updating.
So inside this consumer, then I'm using I mapper inside here, which means I've added a mapping profile
inside the search service and let's open up the one from the search service and I've got the auction
updated going to the item.
So that's being used inside the constructor here.
Then I've got just a right line just to let me know that the consuming action is taking place.
Then I've got the mapping to go from the message to the item and then I've got the result stored in
a result when we do use the update command.
So this does give us a result to say that something has happened.
So I've used that just to throw an exception if there was a problem updating MongoDB, but in the case
that we can update it, then all I've done is I've gone out to use the match command.
To find the item from the database.
And then I've said to modify only these properties of the item that we got from the database originally
and then execute async and then that will update the database.
So that takes care of the auction updated consumer.
And if we go back to the controller, the delete one is a bit easier.
And if we take a look at what's inside here, we don't need a mapper for this because all we've got
is an ID that we need to pass for the auction deleted.
So what we've got here after the context auctions remove, I've got the publish for the auction deleted
and we just need to populate the ID of the auction.
And because the auction ID here is good, we need to make this a string because that's what we're sending
or have in our auction deleted contract.
So no mapping involved on this one.
And then inside the search service, what we have is an auction deleted consumer.
And all we need to do for this one, we don't need to inject anything here.
So I've just got the console right line to say I'm consuming the auction deleted and then simply all
we need to do is use the delete async method, pass in the context dot message ID, which is the auction
ID and that goes ahead and deletes that item from our Mongo database.
Once again, we do get a result back from this method.
I'm not quite sure why it is.
When we save one we do not get something returned, but we do in this case.
And if that doesn't work, once again, I've just used the opportunity to throw a new message exception
and just saying problem deleting auction.
So once you have those in place, you'll be able to run the test and they all should pass.
So congratulations.
If you did manage to get that working and if you didn't, don't worry, just update your code to reflect
the same as what I've done in here or a version of it and see if you can get the test passing that way.
Now, during this section, we've probably got a lot of data inconsistency from various testing and
messing around with what we've been doing.
So before we do finish this section, I'm just going to stop all of my services, the auction service
and the search service.
And I'm also going to clear out what's in Docker, compose and restart the services so that the databases
are clean and we've got clean databases before we move on to the next section.
So I'm just going to do a Docker compose down, which I know is going to remove all the data inside
those databases as well.
And once they've stopped, I'm just going to execute a docker compose up.
To make sure that and to make sure that is up and running.
And then I'm just going to simply restart the auction service and I'm going to restart the search service
as well.
And the databases should now be clean and we should be back to ten.
Auctions in each service.
So this brings us to the end of this section.
So as per usual, at the end of any section, I'm just going to commit my changes into source control.
So I'm going to say git add followed by a period and git commit dash m and say end of section four,
and then I'm just going to push these changes to GitHub.
So I'm just going to say git push origin main and press return.
And we'll wrap up with a summary.